Guide to the Claude McKay Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject Files, 1927-43; Series IV; 0.42; (1 box)
  - TOPICAL
    - Miscellaneous, 1928-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 536)
      See also: Oversize, Box 20, folders 629-31
    - North Africa, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 537)
    - Politics, 1936, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 538)
    - Race, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 539)
    - Religion, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 540)
    - Russia, 1927-37, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 541)
    - Spain and Spanish Civil War, 1935-38, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 542)
- Photographs, 1920-71; Series V; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series V, Photographs, is organized into five subseries: Family, Snapshots of McKay, Other People, Places and Other.
  - FAMILY
    - Father and daughter, 1942-78, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 543)
      With Selma Burke, Carl Cowl and others
  - SNAPSHOTS OF MCKAY
    - McKay Alone
      - In [L'Edaga?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 544)
      - In Morocco, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 545)
      - In St. Petersburg, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 546)
      - Other, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 547)
    - McKay with Others
      - Abdullah, [C.-Moulay?], 1932 (Box 18, Folder 548)
      - Bukharin, Nicolai Ivanovich Zinovyev, Grigory Yevseyevich, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 549)
      - Friedmann, Georges, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 550)
      - Holitscher, Arthur Zetkin, Klara, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 551)
      - Huiswoud, Otto, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 552)
      - In Russia, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 553-554)
      - In Tangiers, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 555)
      - Other, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 556)
  - OTHER PEOPLE
    - Allen, James S., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 557)
    - Armstrong, Louis, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 558)
      Photo by Rockwell O'Keefe, Inc.
    - Baker, Josephine, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 559)
    - Barthé, Richmond (Box 18, Folder 560)
    - [Baumgarten?], Karl, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 561)
    - Bennett, Gwendolyn, 1924 (Box 18, Folder 562)
    - Bullitt, Louise Bryant, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 563)
    - Bukharin, Nicolai Ivanovich Radek, Karl, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 564)
    - Calloway, Cab, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 565)
      Photo by Mills Artists, Inc.
    - Conner, Gordon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 566)
      Photo by Lunceford Artists
    - Crosby, Bob Scott, Raymond, 1937 Nov 20 (Box 18, Folder 567)
      Photo by CBS
    - Ellington, Duke (Box 18, Folder 568)
    - Feckner, A., 1922 (Box 18, Folder 569)
    - Handy, W. C. (William Christopher) Still, William Grant, 1939 (Box 18, Folder 570)
      Photo by New York World's Fair
    - Haussner, [Armand?] (Box 18, Folder 571)
    - Hennacy, Ammon, 1946 Aug 5 (Box 18, Folder 572)
    - Holitscher, Arthur Zetkin, Klara, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 573)
    - Holt, Nora, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 574)
      Photo by Talbot
    - Huggins, Willis N., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 575)
    - [Kamenev, Lev Borisovich?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 576)
    - Larsen, Nella, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 577)
    - Lenin, Vladimir Ilích, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 578)
    - Negro Writers Guild, 1937 May 25 (Box 18, Folder 579)
    - Radek, Karl, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 580)
    - Reid, Richard O., n.d. (Box 18, Folder 581)
    - Robeson, [Paul Jr.?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 582)
    - Salem, Hanem, 1937, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 583)
    - [Southernaires?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 584)
      Photo by Ray Lee Jackson, NBC
    - Trotsky, Leon, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 585)
    - Waller, Fats, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 586)
    - White, Pearl, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 587)
      Photo by DeBarron
    - Zinovyev, Grigory Yevseyevich, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 588)
    - ----, George, 1930 Jul (Box 18, Folder 589)
    - ----, Henry, 1929 Nov (Box 18, Folder 590)
    - ----, [Nile?], n.d. (Box 18, Folder 591)
      Photo by S. Tarr
    - ----, Rex, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 592)
    - Unidentified, 1920-35, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 593-597a)
      Includes photos by Campbell, [Komore Rearden?], James L. Allen and Fax Photo Studio
  - PLACES
    - Claude McKay Secondary School, Clarendon, Jamaica, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 597b)
    - Rabat, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 598)
    - Russia, [ca. 1923] (Box 18, Folder 599)
    - Statue of Liberty, New York City, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 599a)
    - Other, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 600)
    - Other, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 600a)
  - OTHER
    - Bronze figure by Malvina Hoffman, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 601)
      Photo by American Museum of Natural History
    - Goya's "Scena del tre Maggio 1808", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 602)
    - McKay's typewriter, [1971?] (Box 18, Folder 603)
    - Unidentified man by Henri Cartier-Bresson, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 604)
    - Velasquez' "Le filatrici", n.d. (Box 18, Folder 605)
    - Unidentified, 1934, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 606)
- Memorabilia, 1978-90; Series VI; 0.42; (1 box)
  Series VI, Memorabilia, is organized into five subseries: Material Relating to Order of Jamaica Award (1978), Material Relating to McKay Tribute (1979), Material Relating to McKay Dedication (1980), Material Relating to McKay Centennial (1989) and Material Relating to McKay Conference (1990)
  - MATERIAL RELATING TO ORDER OF JAMAICA AWARD
    - Addresses, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 606a)
    - Photographs, [1978] (Box 19, Folder 606b)
  - MATERIAL RELATING TO MCKAY TRIBUTE
    - Claude McKay Secondary School Bulletin, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 607)
    - Clippings, 1979 Dec (Box 19, Folder 608)
      See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 632
    - Program, 1979 Dec 12 (Box 19, Folder 609)
  - MATERIAL RELATING TO MCKAY DEDICATION
    - Clippings, 1980-81 (Box 19, Folder 610)
    - Photographs, 1980 Dec 12 (Box 19, Folder 611)
    - Program, 1980 Dec 12 (Box 19, Folder 612)
    - Other
      - Match case, [1980] (Box 19, Folder 613)
      - Napkin, [1980] (Box 19, Folder 614)
      - Pencils and pens, [1980] (Box 19, Folder 615)
      - T-shirts, [1980] (Box 19, Folder 616-618)
  - MATERIAL RELATING TO MCKAY CENTENNIAL
    - Claude McKay Secondary School Bulletin, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 618a)
    - Clippings, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 618b)
  - MATERIAL RELATING TO MCKAY CONFERENCE
    - Clippings, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 618c)
      See also: Oversize, Box 20, folder 632a
    - Photographs, 1990 Jan (Box 19, Folder 618)
    - Programs, 1990 Jan (Box 19, Folder 618e)
- Oversize, 1.67; (1 box)
  - Envelope from Hope McKay Virtue to Donald Gallop (In Series I), 1964 Apr 29 (Box 20, Folder 619)
  - Galley for "Picket Committee of the Citizens' League for Fair Play" (In Series II), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 620)
  - Saturday review mention of Banjo (In Series II), 1929 Jul 27 (Box 20, Folder 621)
  - Review of Harlem: Negro Metropolis (In Series II), 1940 Oct 17 (Box 20, Folder 622)
  - Reviews of Home to Harlem (In Series II) (Box 20, Folder 623)
  - Galley for The Selected Poems of Claude McKay (In Series II), 1950 Mar 23 (Box 20, Folder 624)
  - Galley for The Selected Poems of Claude McKay, with printer's annotations (In Series II), 1952 Jul (Box 20, Folder 625)
  - Interview in Today (In Series III), 1948 Mar 15 (Box 20, Folder 626)
  - Russian poster (In Series III), 1923 (Box 20, Folder 627)
  - New York times magazine article on labor (In Series IV), 1937 Mar 21 (Box 20, Folder 628)
  - Brooklyn Eagle article on photography (In Series IV), 1930 Dec 14 (Box 20, Folder 629)
  - Advertisement (In Series IV), 1935 (Box 20, Folder 630)
  - Map of Bordeaux (In Series IV), n.d. (Box 20, Folder 631)
  - Article on McKay tribute (In Series VI), 1979 Dec 23 (Box 20, Folder 632)
  - Clipping on McKay conference (In Series VI), 1990 Jan 21 (Box 20, Folder 632a)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.42; (1 box) + 1 object
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 1, folder 1 (Box 21, Folder 633)
  - Box 1, folder 12 (Box 21, Folder 634)
  - Box 1, folder 19 (Box 21, Folder 635)
  - Box 1, folder 25 (Box 21, Folder 636)
  - Box 1, folder 30 (Box 21, Folder 637)
  - Box 1, folder 33 (Box 21, Folder 638)
  - Box 2, folder 36 (Box 21, Folder 639)
  - Box 2, folder 37 (Box 21, Folder 640)
  - Box 2, folder 43 (Box 21, Folder 641)
  - Box 2, folder 46 (Box 21, Folder 642)
  - Box 2, folder 49 (Box 21, Folder 643)
  - Box 2, folder 50 (Box 21, Folder 644)
  - Box 2, folder 52 (Box 21, Folder 645)
  - Box 2, folder 54 (Box 21, Folder 646)
  - Box 2, folder 55 (Box 21, Folder 647)
  - Box 2, folder 56 (Box 21, Folder 648)
  - Box 2, folder 58 (Box 21, Folder 649)
  - Box 2, folder 59 (Box 21, Folder 650)
  - Box 3, folder 87 (Box 21, Folder 651)
  - Box 3, folder 89 (Box 21, Folder 652)
  - Box 3, folder 98 (Box 21, Folder 653)
  - Box 4, folder 102 (Box 21, Folder 654)
  - Box 4, folder 108 (Box 21, Folder 655)
  - Box 4, folder 109 (Box 21, Folder 656)
  - Box 4, folder 113 (Box 21, Folder 657)
  - Box 4, folder 115 (Box 21, Folder 658)
  - Box 4, folder 116 (Box 21, Folder 659)
  - Box 4, folder 117 (Box 21, Folder 660)
  - Box 4, folder 130 (Box 21, Folder 661)
  - Box 4, folder 131 (Box 21, Folder 662)
  - Box 5, folder 144 (Box 21, Folder 663)
  - Box 5, folder 160 (Box 21, Folder 664)
  - Box 5, folder 163 (Box 21, Folder 665)
  - Box 5, folder 164 (Box 21, Folder 666)
  - Box 5, folder 169 (Box 21, Folder 667)
  - Box 6, folder 184 (Box 21, Folder 668)
  - Box 6, folder 187 (Box 21, Folder 669)
  - Box 6, folder 192 (Box 21, Folder 670)
  - Box 6, folder 193 (Box 21, Folder 671)
  - Box 6, folder 203 (Box 21, Folder 672)
  - Box 6, folder 204 (Box 21, Folder 673)
  - Box 7, folder 208 (Box 21, Folder 674)
  - Box 7, folder 216 (Box 21, Folder 675)
  - Box 7, folder 227 (Box 21, Folder 676)
  - Box 7, folder 231 (Box 21, Folder 677)
  - Box 7, folder 235 (Box 21, Folder 678)
  - Box 8, folder 257 (Box 21, Folder 679)
  - Box 9, folder 287 (Box 21, Folder 680)
  - Box 9, folder 292 (Box 21, Folder 681)
  - Box 9, folder 294 (Box 21, Folder 682)
  - Box 11, folder 342 (Box 21, Folder 683)
  - Box 11, folder 350 (Box 21, Folder 684)
  - Box 12, folder 370 (Box 21, Folder 685)
  - Box 12, folder 395 (Box 21, Folder 686)
  - Box 13, folder 415 (Box 21, Folder 687)
  - Box 13, folder 431 (Box 21, Folder 688)
  - Box 13, folder 433 (Box 21, Folder 689)
  - Box 15, folder 467 (Box 21, Folder 690)
  - Box 15, folder 468 (Box 21, Folder 691)
  - Box 15, folder 469 (Box 21, Folder 692)
  - Box 16, folder 512 (Box 22, Folder 693)
  - Box 16, folder 513 (Box 21, Folder 694)
  - Box 16, folder 517 (Box 21, Folder 695)
  - Box 19, folder 618b (Box 21, Folder 696)
  - Box 18, folder 547 (Box cs, Folder 697)
  - Box 18, folder 556 (Box cs, Folder 698)
  - Box 18, folder 597a (Box cs, Folder 699)
  - Box 18, folder 600a (Box cs, Folder 700)